<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Information for Dame Helenor, Issobel, and Margaret Nicolsons, Sir John Schaw of Greenock, Sir James Dunbar of Mochrum, and Mr. Thomas Nicolson younger of Balcaskie their husbands. Against Sir Thomas Nicolson of Tillcultrie.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 38 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B03778</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52529161</idno>
  <idno type="VID">178811</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240862711</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I163C</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R178644</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">52529161</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B03778)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 178811)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2771:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Information for Dame Helenor, Issobel, and Margaret Nicolsons, Sir John Schaw of Greenock, Sir James Dunbar of Mochrum, and Mr. Thomas Nicolson younger of Balcaskie their husbands. Against Sir Thomas Nicolson of Tillcultrie.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Includes a copy of the matrimonial contract between Sir Thomas Nicolson and Lady Margaret Livingston, and of the bond of provision from Sir Thomas Nicolson to his daughters.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: creased with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Nicolson, Helenor, --  Dame --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term type="personal_name">Nicolson, Isobel, fl. 1695 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term type="personal_name">Nicolson, Margaret, fl. 1695 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term type="personal_name">Schaw, John, --  Sir, d. 1752 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term type="personal_name">Dunbar, James, --  Sir, 1667 or 68-1737 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term type="personal_name">Nicolson, Thomas, --  younger, --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term type="personal_name">Nicolson, Thomas, fl. 1713 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Inheritance and succession --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:178811:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:178811:1"/>
            <head>INFORMATION <hi>For Dame</hi> Helenor, Issobel, <hi>and</hi> Margaret Nicolsons, <hi>Sir</hi> John Schaw <hi>of</hi> Greenock, <hi>Sir</hi> James Dumbar <hi>of</hi> Mochrum, <hi>and Mr.</hi> Thomas Nicolson <hi>younger of</hi> Balcaskie <hi>their Husbands.</hi> Against <hi>Sir</hi> Thomas Nicolson <hi>of</hi> Tillicultrie.</head>
            <p>THe Estate of <hi>Carnock</hi> and <hi>Plane</hi> being purchased by Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson,</hi> he settled the same in favours of himself and his Heirs whatsomever, and Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his eldest Son having succeed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed as his Heir of Line, and being Minor, least he might be injured by his Transactions, and that he might be governed and advised by his Friends, he choices Sir <hi>Thomas Hope</hi> of <hi>Craighall,</hi> Sir <hi>Alexander Gibson</hi> of <hi>Durie,</hi> Sir <hi>John Hope</hi> younger of <hi>Craighall.</hi> Sir <hi>James Foulis</hi> of <hi>Collingtoun,</hi> Sir <hi>Leuis Stuart</hi> of <hi>Kirkhill,</hi> Sir <hi>James Nicolson</hi> of <hi>Cockburn-peth, John Nicolson</hi> of <hi>Poltoun,</hi> Mr. <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> Advocat, and Mr. <hi>James Baird,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Robert Nicolson</hi> Commissars of <hi>Edinburgh</hi> to be his Curators, whereupon there is an Act extracted under the hand of the Commissar-Clerk of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> dated the 2d day of <hi>April</hi> 1646 years.</p>
            <p>Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> while Minor enters into a Contract of Marriage with Lady Margaret <hi>Living<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stoun,</hi> Daughter to the Earl of <hi>Linlithgow,</hi> whereby he provids his Estate to the Heirs-Male of that Marriage, and obliges him and his Heirs male and Successors whatsoever, to pay Portions to the Daughters of that Marriage, but this Contract though it bear with his Curators consent, yet it is not subscribed by them.</p>
            <p>Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> of <hi>Tillicultrie</hi> serves himself Heir-male in general to the said deceaff Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> the Contracter, and the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Daughters, who were served Heirs of Line in special, and infest to Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson,</hi> thereafter Lord <hi>Napeir</hi> their Nephew Raise a Process against the said <hi>Tillicultrie,</hi> for declaring the Right of the foresaid Estate to belong to them as Heirs of Line, conform to their special Retour and Infeftment, and that by the foresaid Minut of Contract, there was no Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teration of the Succession from the Heirs whatsoever to the Heirs-male, and that the Minut was Null being entered into by a Minor having Curators, without their consent, and the said <hi>Tillicultrie</hi> raises a Counter-declarator at his instance against them, for declaring the Estate to belong to him as Heir-male, because by the foresaid Contract, the same is provided to the Heirs-male of the Marriage, and in all the Obligements upon Sir <hi>Thomas,</hi> he obliges his Heirs-male in performance, which he would ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver have done it he had not designed them to have succeeded to his Estate.</p>
            <p>These mutual Processes being long and fully debate, and much retarded by <hi>Tilliciultrie,</hi> by the then prevailing influence, even to that rate, that the late King interposed when the Process was to be advised by the Lords, and by his Warrand caused his Advocat take up the same, where it lodged till the present Establishment of the Session, that the Action being again wakned, and of new fully heard and debate; The Lords found and declared, that there was no Alteration or Change of the Succession and former Sttlement of the Estate of <hi>Carnock</hi> and <hi>Plain</hi> provided to Heirs whatsoever, from the saids Heirs whatsoever, to, and in favours of Heirs male, either exprest in, or imported by the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said Minut of Contract Matrimonial, betwixt the said Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> and Lady <hi>Margaret Living<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stoun,</hi> or yet expressed in, or imported by the Bond of Provision granted by the said Sir <hi>Thomas Nicol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son</hi> to the said <hi>Helener, Isobel Anna</hi> and <hi>Margaret Nicolsons</hi> his Daughters, and fand and declared that the said deceast Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> was Minor, the time of entering unto the foresaid Minut of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tract, and that the said Minut was entered into without his Curators subscribing the same; and that it is proven by the Act of Curatory produced; that the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> had Curators at the time, and that by the said Contract, the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> could not without Advice and Consent of his Curators alter the former Setlement of his Estate provided in favours of his Heirs whatsomever, to a Tailzie in favours of the Heirs-male: And that the foresaid Deed and alteration, albeit it had imported a Tailzie and Alteration of the Succession, which
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:178811:2"/> it did not, was void and null, and therefore found and declared that the said <hi>Helenor, Isobel</hi> and <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garet Nicolsons,</hi> Heirs Portioners of Line, in special served and retoured to the said <hi>Thomas</hi> Lord <hi>Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peir,</hi> and their Husbands foresaids for their Interests, have good and undoubted Right to the Lands and Baronie of <hi>Carnock</hi> and <hi>Plain,</hi> as the Decreet extracted thereupon, of the date the 3d day of <hi>Feb.</hi> 1691 years more fully bears.</p>
            <p>Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> of <hi>Tillicoutrie</hi> having protested for remeid of Law against the foresaid Sentence though several sessions of Parliament have been since, yet he never insisted therein, but the Heirs of Line were necessitat to apply to the Parliament, and procure a Warrand for citeing him to insist upon the grounds of his Appeal, which after he had much waved, was at last given in, and both Parties heard before the Committee for Privat Affairs.</p>
            <p>The said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> Procurators first urged, that the Contract was a plain Alteration of the Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cession of that Estate from the Heirs whatsoever to the Heirs-male, and so that he was laesed by the Lords Interloquitor, for by the Contract he provides his Lady to the Baroney of <hi>Plane,</hi> and takes her bound to pay to his Heir-male what the same Baroney pays more than four thousand merks of yearly Rent. 2. He obliges his Heirs-male and Successors in Warradice of the said provision. 3. He ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liges himself to provide his Estate to the Heirs-male of the Marriage, and obliges the Heir-male in payment of particulal Sums to the Daughters of that Marriage, and that the Contract should be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended by advice of Men of Law; from all which he alledged that it was evident, that by that Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tract it was designed that the Estate should go to the Heirs-male, as was the common Custom of ancient Feus.</p>
            <p>It is Answered for the Heirs of Line, That the Succession to Lands is determined by the Tenor of the former Infeftments, and which no design nor resolution can alter, without an plain Resignation or Obligement to that effect: And it is not contraverted but Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> the Acquirers Infest<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment is to the Heirs whatsomever, and so the Service and Retour of the Heirs of Line, as Heirs to the Lord <hi>Napeir</hi> their Nephew, is conform and agreeable to the Infeftments of that Estate; and so de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clares and compleats their Right, unless an plain Obligement or Resignation to the contrair did appear. And as to the Contract produced and debated upon, there is not the least shaddow of change or al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teration therein exprest or imported, for though the Contract obleige the Heirs Male, yet that is no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing, because all Debitors and Obligants, both in their Provisions to their Ladies, and their Bonds to their Creditors, bind their Heirs, as well Male of Tailzie, Conquest and Provision, as of Line, which is in order to the Creditors security, but has no relation or design to alter the Succession of the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son Bonud, and it does not import, that by the same Contract the <hi>overplus</hi> Rent is to be payed to the Heir Male, because by the Contract, he provided the Estate to the Heir Male of that Marriage, who exhilted, and who thereby had right to that <hi>overplus</hi> Rent, so that two things are necessarly to be considered: 1. That no Design to make a Tailze doth import a Tailzie, and therefore although the Contract had born, that the Contracter designed to have tailzied his Estate, which is not done, or by any Write under his Hand, had exprest such an Intention, yet if there had been no express Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligement upon him and his Heirs whatsomever, in favours of himself, and his Heirs of Teilzie, no Lawyer will assert that there is a Tailzie implyed, for Tailzies being a cutting off the Natural and Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gal Line of Succession, are not to be drawn from Conjectures or Intentions, but from positive Deeds; and the truth is, this Contract being writen upon the supposition and mistake that the ancient Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rities were to Heirs Male, by the direction of a <hi>Minor,</hi> ignorant of his Affairs, without consent of his Curators, does not so much as import a remot intention to change the course of Succession. 2. All that in sense can be thought to be imported by that Minut, has happened and is fulfilled; Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> had an Heir Male of that Marriage, who was likewise Heir of Line, and suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeded him, and the Lord <hi>Napeir</hi> succeeded to him again as Heir of Line; And since there was no Obligement upon the Heir Male, of that Marriage, or this Heir of Line to transmit his Estate to his Heirs Male, the Law did convey it to his Heirs of Line.</p>
            <p>Whereas it was alleged that he took his Heirs Male bound to pay Portions to his Daughters, which is an Demonstration that he did not design his Daughters to succeed.</p>
            <p>It was Answerd, that he having married the Earl of <hi>Linlithgows</hi> Daughter, the Earl and his Friends thought it reasonable, that the whole Estate should go to the Heirs of that Marriage, but that being refused by Sir <hi>Thomas,</hi> it has been concerted, that the Estate should go to the Heirs Male of that Marriage, And in case these failzied, and that Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> had Heirs Male of another Marriage, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by the Daughters would be secluded from Succession, therefore he bound his Heirs Male in payment of the Portions to his Daughters; and <hi>de facto,</hi> his Son Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> did succeed: And after Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> the Contracter is fourty Years of age, gives an Bond of Provision in favours of these Daughters, whereby he binds his Heirs whatsomever, which is a sufficient Document that he neither under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stood nor designed any alteration of his Succession by the former contract, which could not be done but <hi>habili modo,</hi> by plain obligement to that purpose and resignation.</p>
            <p>What ever Reason there might be where Feues were granted gratuitously for Military Service, that the Masculine Line should succeed, yet this being <hi>feudum novum</hi> purchased by Sir <hi>Thomas Nicol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son,</hi> to him, and his Heirs, whatsomever the Tenor of his Infeftment is the Rule of Succession, and takes of all Presumption in favours of the Heir-male.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:178811:2"/>
            <p>It were tedious and unnecessary to make Commentaries upon all the several Clauses of the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tract wherein mention is made of Heirs-male, seing the most considerable Clauses have been already taken notice of, and the repeating of Heirs-male so often, did partly proceed from the mistake of the first Infeftments, and partly from the express Intention that the Contracter had; that his own Heirs-male, tho of an other Marriage, should succeed before his Daughters of the Marriage with my Lady <hi>Margaret Livingstoun,</hi> and it is not to be imagined, that the Ladies Honourable Relations would have agreed to any settlement, whereby the Daughters of that Marriage would have been excluded from Succession, if Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> had died without Male Issue, and if the Contracter had had any such design, it had been easie in the Course of twenty years life that followed afterwards, to have complea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted it, which he never did.</p>
            <p>As there is no alteration of the Succession exprest, or imported from this Contract, so the Lords likewise found the same null, as being entered into by a Minor, having Curators without their Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent.</p>
            <p>Against which Branch of the Decreet, <hi>Tillicoutrie</hi> urged. 1. That it was not proven that Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> was Minor, the Extract of his Age not being an sufficient Probation. 2. The Act of Cura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tory did not prove, unless the Warrand thereof subscribed by the Curators were produced. 3. It was not proven that the Curators were alive the time of the Contract. 4. Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> was not thereby lesed. 5. He did not rev<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ck <hi>inter annos utiles,</hi> but on the contrair, did homologat the same by granting the Bond of Provision to his Daughters</p>
            <p>To this it is Answered, that as the Contract does not in the least insinuat any Alteration of the Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cession from the Heirs whatsoever to the Heirs-male, so the same proves the Minority of Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> the Granter, in regaird it bears with consent of his Curators, which is never adhibite but to Minors, and seing <hi>Tillcoultrie</hi> makes use thereof for his Tailzie, he must like ways make use of the same for proving the Minority, seing he cannot both approbat and reprobat the same Writ, and though the Extract of his Age bearing so many honourable witnesses <hi>in re tam antiqua,</hi> be a sufficient Probation, yet it is here more full, being adminiculat by this Contract, bearing with consent of Curators, and by a Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge granted by him <hi>in anno</hi> 1649, with consent of his Curators to the Lord <hi>Belhaven</hi> of certain An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nualrents, which proves his Minority that year, and so infallably in the year 1648 preceeding, in which the contraverted Minut of Contract is dated.</p>
            <p>As to the second, the Act of Curotory is produced, and the Decreet of the Lords opponed, bearing the same to have been compared with the Record, and to quadrat therewith, and to be marked in the Minut-book; and besides all this, there is produced a Factory by the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> with consent of his Curators thereto subscribing to <hi>William Livingstoun,</hi> appointing him Factor <hi>in anno</hi> 1647 short<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly after the said Act of Curatory. 2. The Contract pursued upon <hi>in anno</hi> 1648 bears with consent of his Curators. 3. The Discharge of Annualrents to <hi>Belhaven</hi> in <hi>anno</hi> 1649, is granted by him and his Curators, each of which <hi>per se</hi> do prove the Curatory, and fully astruct the Act and Acceptation.</p>
            <p>As to the third, That it is not proven that the Curators were alive the time of the Contract.</p>
            <p>It is Answered, That the Curators are presumed alive, unless they had been proven dead, and here their being alive, appears by the Contract which bears with their consent. 2, The Discharge to <hi>Belhaven</hi> is subscribed by them one year thereafter 1649, which necessarily inferrs that they were alive the year preceeding 1648: And it is notour to many in the Parliament, that most of them were alive for many years thereafter, and Sir <hi>James Fowls</hi> of <hi>Collington</hi> is but lately dead.</p>
            <p>To the fourth, That Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> was not thereby laesed, It is Answered, that the Deeds of <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors</hi> having Curators, without their consent, are <hi>ipso jure</hi> null, and so Laesion needs not be alledged, which has been so often decided, that the same is now become an uncontraverted Principle, as may appear by the Decision, the 7 <hi>December</hi> 1666, Sir <hi>George Mekenzie contra Fareholm,</hi> and the 25 of <hi>December</hi> 1667, <hi>inter eosdem;</hi> And the 9 of <hi>December</hi> 1632, <hi>Maxwel contra</hi> the Earl of <hi>Nithsdale,</hi> and innumirable more Decisions observed both by <hi>Dury</hi> and <hi>Stair;</hi> And if <hi>Minors</hi> having Curators were obliged to Instruct laesion in the deeds done without their consent, then it were of no value or import to choose Curators, because where laesion is instructed, <hi>Minors</hi> are restored: however even against these deeds to which the Curators consent, but Curators being chosen, the want of their consent to the <hi>Minors</hi> Deed, renders the Deed null. And the Law gives this Reason for having Curators, <hi>Magis decorum &amp; honestum esse in tempore occurrere &amp; providere ne minores capiantur, quam ut assiduis in plorationibus tribunalia personent,</hi> which fully signifies, that where they want Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rators, they must apply to the Judicatories, but where they have Curators, that that application is prevented by the nullity of the deed: And in general, where ever the Law requires a specifick Form or Solemnity in any act, if that Act be done without observing that Form or Solemnity it is null: Now it will not, nor cannot be contraverted, but that the Law requires that <hi>Minors</hi> having Curators ought to be authorized, when they enter into Contracts mutually obligato<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, and of vast importance for their Families: And therefore the Contracter here being <hi>Minor,</hi> and having entred into a Contract without observing the Forms of Law, the Deed is unquestiona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly null, and the very contract it self, if it did import a Tailzie as it does not, were a sufficient laesion, being the alteration of the Succession from the Heirs whatsomever, to the Heirs Male: And besides, there is an other obvious laesion, for thereby Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> provides his Lady to her Jointure, though the Marriage dissolve within the Year.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:178811:3"/>
            <p>To the Fifth, That he did not Revock <hi>inter annos utiles,</hi> but Homologat the same, by granting a Bond of Provision to his Daughters.</p>
            <p>To this it is answered, That the same is no ground of Appeal, because not alledged before the Lords, nor could be; for null Deeds need no Revocation. Deeds of Minors that require Revoca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion are such as of their own nature subsist, and are Obligator: such as the Deeds of Minors want<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Curators, and the Deeds of Minors with the consent of their Curators. But the Deeds of Minors ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving Curators, without their Consent being <hi>ipso jure</hi> Null, <hi>nullo tractu temporis possunt convalescere,</hi> And n<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> forraign Custom can regulat this Case, which is so fully and plainly regulat and determined by our Law.</p>
            <p>As to the Homologation alledged upon. It is answered, 1. There is no Tailzie by the Contract.</p>
            <p n="2">2. The Bond of Provision granted on Death-bed, has no relation to the Tailzie, and so is no Homo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>logation thereof. 3. Homologation is only inferred, where the Act of Homologation can be ascri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bed to no other Deed, but the Deed Homologat; but here Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> the Granter of the Bond of P<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> not Found the same upon the foresaid Contract but upon the Tyes lying upon him by t<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Law of God and Nature to provide his Daughters, he having then an Heir-male of his own Body alive who did succeed him, his Daughters being absolutly unprovided: and so it is no Homologation of the Contract, but the Effect of his Duty. 2. The Bond clearly Insinuats the contrare, for the same binds his Heirs whatsomever, without any mention of his Heirs-male: And albeit it requires the Granters Son, or any other who should succeed to his Estate, to fulfil the Provisions to the Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters; yet that doth not import, that there was a Tailzie, and the Daughters excluded. But the Granter having a Son at the time, who was to succeed him, and might have Children, who whither Male or Female, would have excluded his own Daughters, being the Representatives of the eldest Son; therefore he requires in general, all whoever should succeed him, to fulfil the Provisions to his saids Daughters.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>This being Debate before the Committee for privat Affairs, it was their Opinion, that the Protest for remeid of Law at</hi> Till coultries <hi>Instance against the Co-heirs of</hi> Carnock, <hi>be Rejected, and the Sentence of the Lords of Session do stand in Force.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now having gone through the Reasons of <hi>Tillicoultries</hi> Appeal, it remains to give some sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction to the Amusements that he hath insert in his Information. And first, whereas it was pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended, that this Tailzie was designed for preservation of the Memory of Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson,</hi> which was indeed very worthy, and deserved to be represented; and that the Minut being to be extended at the fight of men of Law, no Lawyer would have Advised to extend it in any other Terms, than of a Tailzie to the Heirs-male. It is Answered, that if the design had been to continue, Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Memory it has been very ill laid; for the Lord <hi>Napier</hi> who was Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> Heir-male, lay under no Restraint not to change his Name, and smoother the Remembrance of his Family: and <hi>Tillicoultries</hi> Affairs give no Prospect that it can continue in the Name of <hi>Nicolson.</hi> And as to the Pretence, that a Lawyer would have extended the Minut in the Terms of a Tailxie to the Heirs-male. It is answered, it is likely enough indeed, that <hi>Tillicoultries</hi> Lawyers would now extend it so: but no Lawyer knowing the Provision of the Original Infeftments, could upon any Pretence of this <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> have fram'd a Tailzie; for it is observable, that in the whole Contract there is not an Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligement to provide, or resign in favours of the Heirs-male indefinitly; and therefore no body could have extended such an Obligement in their favours, without an extraordinary Byase. 2. Whereas it is pretended, that the Decreet of Session was carried by a casting Vote, and the best part of the Lawyers were against it; and therefore ought to have the less weight. It is answered, That this Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledgiance is equally false and Irrelevant, and therefore deserves very little Consideration; for the Business was not decided by a narrow Plurality; and if it had been a single Vote as is pretended; yet is a Decreet of Session, and ought to be of great Force, unless the same were found unjust, which it cannot for the Reasons foresaid.</p>
            <p>In Respect whereof, the Decreet of the Lords of Session in favours of the Heirs of Line, ought to be sustained, and the Heir-male condemned in large Expenses, for Appealing from the Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence of the saids Lords without Ground.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="marriage_contract">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:178811:3"/>
            <head>COPIE Contract Matrimoniall, betwixt Sir <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Nicolson,</hi> and Lady <hi>Margaret Livingstoun.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>AN Minute of an Contract Matrimonial, to be extended betwixt the Honourable parties following, To wit, <hi>Sir Tho: Nicolson</hi> of <hi>Carnock</hi> Knight, with advice &amp; con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent of Dam <hi>Issobel Henderson</hi> Lady <hi>Carnock</hi> his Mother &amp; his <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> Cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ators, under Subscriving on the one part, and Lady <hi>Margaret Livinstoun,</hi> second Lawful Daughter to an Noble and Potent Earl, <hi>Alexander</hi> Earl of <hi>Linlithgow,</hi> Lord <hi>Livinstoun</hi> and <hi>Callendar, &amp;c.</hi> With advice and content of the said Noble Earl. <hi>James</hi> Earl of <hi>Callender,</hi> Lord <hi>Livingstoun</hi> of <hi>Almond,</hi> and <hi>Falkirk</hi> her Uncle, and of an Noble Lord, <hi>George</hi> Lord <hi>Livingstoun</hi> her Brother, and they for themselves and their own interests following; and the saids Noble Earl <hi>Allexander,</hi> Earl of <hi>Linlithgow,</hi> and <hi>George</hi> Lord <hi>Livingstoun</hi> his Son, taking the burden upon them for her, as Tutors, Guiders, and Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strators to her by the Law on the other part in manner after specified; That is to say, the saids Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> and Lady <hi>Margaret,</hi> with consent above mentioned, has accepted, and be thir presents, accepts either of them, others to be their Lawful Spouses, and Faithfully promises and oblidges them to Solemnize the said Bond of Matrimony betwixt them in face of Holy Kirk betwixt the date Heir of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> day of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> nixt to come, or sooner if both par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties shall think expedient, in respect of the whilk Marriage, and of the summ of Money after mentioned, to be payed in name of Tochat good; The said Sir <hi>Thomas,</hi> with advice and consent of his said Mother and Curators above named, binds and oblidges him, his Heirs and Successors with all possible diligence before the Solemnization of the said Marriage to infest and cease the said Lady <hi>Margaret</hi> his promised Spouse in her Virginity in Lifrent, during all the <gap reason="illegible: page creased" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> of <hi>Plain,</hi> with manner, place, Houses biggings, Yeards, Orchyeards, Woods Fishings, Coals, Coal-heughs, Lyme, Lyme stone, parts, pendickles, and pertinents thereof whatsomever, lying within the Sherriffdom of <hi>Stirling;</hi> And that by his Two several Charters, containing preceipt of Seasin thereintil, and thereof, Bearing the holding to be of the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Heirs Male, and Successours in Fee, Blench Ferar for payment of an pennies <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> money at <hi>Whitesunday</hi> yearly, upon the ground of the saids lands in name or Blench Ferra, if the samen be is required. And the other of the saids Charters, Bear and the Holding to be free, The said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> and his foresaids of his immediate Superiours of the saids Louds, si<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>like, and als freely in all respects as he holds the samen himself, and that either by resignation of Confirmation, as best shall please the said Lady <hi>Margaret</hi> and the saids Father, Uncle, and Brother, and for that effect to make particular Charters and procur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>atories of Resignation as oft, and whensoever he shall be desired thereto, &amp; whille Infeftment of the Lands and others above written, to be made and granted to the said Lady <hi>Margaret</hi> in manner above contained, She with consent above mentioned accepts in Contentation to her of all other Conjunct fie Liferent terce Right whatsomever, whilk she may ask or crave or may fall to her of any other of the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Lands be decease, if it shall happen her to survive him with sufficient clause of Warrandice to be contained in the saids Charters. Likeas the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> be the Tenor hereof with consent of his Mother and Curators a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bovenamed, now as if the saids Charters and Infeftments were alreadie past and perfected; and then as now binds &amp; obleidges him his Heirs Male of Tailzie and provision, Assigneys and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessors, to warrand all and hail the saids lands and Barronties of plain parts pendicles and Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinents thereof foresaid Lynud as said is, to be safe &amp; sure to the said Ladie <hi>Margaret</hi> his promised Spouse in Liferent, during all the dayes of her Lifetime from all perrils Dangers, and inconvenien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies may fall thereto at al hands, and against all deadly, and that the said Lady <hi>Margaret</hi> shall immediatly after his decease enter to the peaceable Possession of the saids Lands and pertinents thereof, uplifting of the Males and Duties of the samen, seting, using and Disponing thereupon as she shall think good, during her lifetime, and that notwithstanding of the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Death within a year after the said Marriage, and of any Law or Statute made or to be made in the contrair, and wherewith he with consent of his said Mother and Curators above named
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:178811:4"/> has Dispensed, and be thir presents Dispenses for ever, providing the said Lady <hi>Margaret</hi> be comptable, and pay to his Heirs Male what the saids Lands shall pay, and be of more worth nor 4000 Merks Money, and siklike, with consent foresaid, to build upon the ground of the saids Lands to the said Ladie <hi>Margaret,</hi> at the sight of the saids Father, Uncle, or Brother, an sufficient dwelling House for her to remain in, agreeable to one of her qualitie and degree, and in like manner, the said Sir <hi>Thomas,</hi> with consent above mentioned, binds and oblidges him and his foresaids, That the Heirs Male to be procreat betwixt him and his said promised Spouse shall not only succeed to the hail Lands, Barronies, Heritages and summs of Money, whilk he presently has pertaining to him, but also to all and whatsomever he shall happen to conquess in the said Ladie <hi>Margaret</hi> her lifetime, in respect whereof, and for the better provision of the Heirs famale, that shall happen to be procreat betwixt him and his said future Spouse failzing of Heirs Male procreat betwixt them, And the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> with consent above written, Binds &amp; oblidges him his Heirs Male &amp; successors whatsomever thankfully to pay and deliver to the saids Heirs Famale if there be any, the Summ of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> If their be two toeither of them the summ of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> and if their be three more, the summ of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> To be devided amongst them in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner following; That is to say, to the eldest the summ of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> And the rest thereof to be equaly devided amongst the rest of the saids Daughters or Heirs Famale, and that how soon, as it shall happen the saids Heirs Famale to come to the age of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> years compleat, during the whilk time the said <gap reason="illegible: page creased" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> his Heirs Male and Assigneys whatsomever shall be bound and obliged to entertain the saids Heir female in Bed, Board, Abulziement and other things necessary according to their Estrte and qualitie at the sight foresaid, for the whilk causes the said noble Earl <hi>Alexander</hi> Earl of <hi>Linlithgow</hi> and with advice and consent of the said Noble Earl <hi>James</hi> Earl of <hi>Callendar</hi> his Brother, and <hi>George</hi> Lord <hi>Livingstoun</hi> his Son, binds and obleidges him, his Heirs, Executors and Assigneys thankfully to content, pay and deliver to the said Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> his Heirs and Assigneys in name of Tochar-Good, with his said Daughter the summ of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> betwixt the date hereof, and the feast and Term of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> in the Year of GOD 16 <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> years but longer delay, together with the summ of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap>
               <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> expences in case of failzie; Finally both parties are content, and consents that this present Minut be extended in ample form be advice of Men of Judgement, betwixt the date hereof, and the <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> day of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> next to come, and after the extension thereof, both the saids Parties binds and obliges their Heirs and Successors to subscrive the same estably &amp; lovingly, &amp; the partie failzied obliges him &amp; is foresaids, to pay to the partie obser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver and repair the summ of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> money above written for not performing of the<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Promisses. And for the more <gap reason="illegible: page creased" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> both the <gap reason="illegible: page creased" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nut; with the Contract to be extended hereupon be insert and Registrat in the Books of Counsel and Session: and a Decreet of the Lords thereof interponed thereto with Letters of Horning on six days, and all other Executorials and Letters necessar in form as effeits may pass thereupon, and to that effect constitutes <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> their Procurators, In Witness whereof (written be <hi>Robert Main</hi> Servitor to Mr. <hi>Andrew Ker</hi> Sherriff and Town Clerk of <hi>Linlithgow</hi>) Both the saids Parties have subscri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved thit Presents at <hi>Linlithgow</hi> &amp; <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> the twentie two &amp; <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> dayes of <hi>August,</hi> and <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> the year of GOD One thousand six hundred and fourtie eight, years; Before thir Witnesses <hi>James</hi> Lord <hi>Ochiltree William Drummond</hi> of <hi>Rickartoun,</hi> Mr. <hi>George Dundass</hi> of <hi>Maner,</hi> and <hi>George Bell</hi> Provost of <hi>Linlithgow, Robert Stewars</hi> Burgess thereof, and the said Mr. <hi>Andrew Ker</hi> Witnesses to the saids Sir <hi>Thomas</hi> Lady <hi>Margaret,</hi> Earl of <hi>Linlithgow,</hi> and his Ladies Subscriptions.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="bond_of_provision">
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:178811:4"/>
            <head>Double Bond of Provision, <hi>Sir</hi> Thomas Nicolson <hi>to his Daughters.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>BE it kend to all Men, be thit present Letters, Me Sir <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> of <hi>Carnock</hi> Knight, For as meikle as, <hi>Helenor, Isobel, Anna,</hi> and <hi>Margaret Nicolsons,</hi> my Lawful Daughters, are not provided to a Competance of Means, whereby they may (at their mature Age) have Marriadge, or otherwayes live in a Rank and Condition, according to their Birth; And seeing I am bound by the Law of GOD and Nature, to provide them ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to my Ability and Estate. Therefore Wit ye me to be bound and ablidged, Likeas, I be the Tenor hereof, Bind and Oblidges me, my Heirs Executers and Successors to me, in my Lands and Heritages wha<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>somever, to pay and deliver to my saids Daughters, the Summs of Money after specified, in manner at the times, and with the Provisions after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, every one of them their own parts, as is after devided. <hi>To wit,</hi> To the said <hi>Helenor,</hi> the Summ of twelve thousand Merks <hi>Scots</hi> Money, To the said <hi>Isobel,</hi> the Summ of ten thousand Merks, To the said <hi>Anna,</hi> the Summ of eight thousand Merks, and to the said <hi>Margaret,</hi> the Summ of six thousand Merks, Money foresaid, and that immediatly at their Age of Fifteen years compleat, or if it shall happen them to marry before that time, I De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare and Ordain the foresaids Provisions to be payed to them immediatly after their Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Marriadge, with the Provision and Condition alwayes, that in case it shall happen any of my saids Daughters to depart this mortal Life before their Marriadge, or within year and day after their Marriadge. In that Case, their Provision above specified, is and shall be declaed void and null, and as if this present Bond had not been granted to the Daughter de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceased, and that <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> my eldest Lawful Son, or any other my Heirs and Succes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sors, shall not be bound and oblidged for the same, But that the foresaids Provisions of the Daughter or Daughters deceased, shall remain and abide with my said Son, or any other who shall succeed to me. And sicklike, That it shall not be Lawful to any of my saids Daughters to assign or leave their forenamed Provisions to any person or persons, in <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ase they shall happen to decease before their Marriadge, under the whilk Provision and Condition this present Bond is granted, and no other wayes; And if it shall happen, that the forenamed Summs be not payed to my saids Daughters at the time, &amp; in maner above; So in that case I obleidge me and my foresaids, To pay to them every one of them for their own parts, as is above exprest, the due and ordinar Annualtent of their saids Provisions, according to the Laws of this Kingdom, and that ay and while they be satisfied and payed of their several Summs abovementioned, and in regard that my saids Daughters have no man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance and aliment at present, in case it should please GOD to remove me before they at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain to their Age and years above specified; Therefore <hi>I</hi> obleidge me and my foresaids, to pay to them and every one of them, or to their Tutors in their Names, the Summ of two hundereth &amp; fifty merks money foresaids yearly, frae the time of my decease, to their Age of teen years, or marriadge, in manner abovementioned. And sicklike, I obleidge and require the said <hi>Thomas Nicolson</hi> my Son, or any other who shall hapen to succeed to my Estate, and as they would expect the LORDS Blessing to prosper with them, That they obtemper, keep, fullfill and perform this present Bond of Provision to my saids Daughters; as they tender and respect their Wellfare, and as the Children gotten of my own Body, and that my Heirs and Successors object nothing against this present Bond, notwithstanding it be done and subscrived <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n lecto egretudinis.</hi> And farder, I will and declare that thir presents shall be reput, holden and sustained as a sufficient Evident, and tye upon my Heirs, Notwithstanding the samen be not a delivered Evident, and found to be in my Custodie after my decease, and seriously recommends to the Honourable Lords of his Majesties Council and Session, and other Judges Competent, that they sustain this present Bond, (as a Tye and Obleidgment upon my Heirs, in case they should object or come in the contrair hereof, And for the more Security, I am content thir Presents be Registrated in the Books of Council and Session, or other Books Competent, that Letter may be direct on six dayes, and Constitutes <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> Our Procurators, in witness whereof, <hi>I</hi> have sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scrived thir presents, (written be <hi>David More</hi> Sherriff Clerk of <hi>Stirling</hi>) at <hi>Carnock</hi> the twenty first of <hi>July.</hi> One thousand six hundered and sixty four years, Before thir Witnesses, <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Livingstoun</hi> Fiar of <hi>Kirkland,</hi> and the said <hi>David More. Sic Subscribitur,</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Tho: Nicolson, Wm: Livingstoun</hi> Witness, <hi>David Moir</hi> Witness.</signed>
            </closer>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:178811:5"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:178811:5"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:178811:6"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>